Ayomide Ibosiola

Technical Recruiter || Software Developer

Nigeria, 100271 http://linkedin.com/in/ayomide-ibosiola, https://calendly.com/ayomideibosiola, https://ayomideibosiola.netlify.app/.

enochibosiola@gmail.com

+234 809 969 1225

Data-driven Technical Recruiter capable of Advanced Boolean Search to identify and mine top candidates with a strong Software Development background; specialized in building web and mobile applications that are aesthetically pleasing and logic driven.

There's nothing like the thrill of a candidate's enthusiastic "Yes!" to an offer, and an equally pleased Hiring Manager who just landed a top performer. Perhaps even more satisfying is successfully recruiting a superstar and then seeing him/her develop a billion-dollar product. Knowing my efforts impact the bottom line keeps me going every day.

In addition to my knowledge base, I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements, currently building experience in Designing HR Processes, Technical Recruiting, Talent Sourcing, Strategy Development, Recruitment and Selection, Employee on-boarding, Payroll Management, HRIS, Employer branding, Learning and development, and other Human Resources functions spanning across Tech Start-ups, Consulting, Financial technology space and NGO sectors.

This has allowed me to stay ahead of the curve and deliver exceptional work to all of my clients.

Work Experience

Frontend Developer || Technical Recruiter

Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd - Bengaluru, Karnataka September 2021 to March 2022

- Pinpoint candidate motivators and used them to successfully recruit quality candidates.
- Analyze job descriptions and communicated with the Hiring Manager (Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd) to clarify terms that could be vague; earned job-satisfaction rates of 95 percent from candidate/company matches as a result of this attention to detail.
- Create new features, functionality and capabilities, specifically in the Contract Management System using ReactJS, Ant Design, Material UI and Java.
- Perform bug fixes and code reviews.
- Recommend solutions for a streamlined, user-friendly interface with the design team.

Technical Copywriter

Marketpath Inc

August 2021 to November 2021

• Gathered and analyzed technical and product information from various sources to document new or changing product functionality.

• Developed product manuals, how-to guides, website help sections, journal articles, and other content that distills technical information with ease and clarity.

Frontend Developer

Mezovest - Lagos May 2021 to June 2021

• Built an online payment gateway that allows businesses make and receive payments across continents, currencies, preferred payment methods, and platforms.

Software Developer

Royal Crystal Airways - Lagos October 2020 to January 2021

- Built the Web Application for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip using ReactJS, Redux, jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Material-UI, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Stylus and ES6.
- Oversaw the outsourced Mobile Application development for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip.

Frontend Developer

Midra Solutions - Lagos January 2019 to March 2020

- Maintained, optimized, troubleshot, and improved websites.
- Created standardized websites and mobile responsive applications using mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Implemented applications and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Built reusable code for future use.

Software Developer (Intern)

Lagosbuild - Lagos

January 2017 to January 2019

- Standardized website output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Integrated data from varios back-end services and databases.

Education

Undergraduate in Microbiology

Obafemi Awolowo University - Osun February 2015 to August 2019

Skills

- · Discretion and decision making
- Communications
- Ability to develop strong relationships and connections
- · Vanilla JavaScript
- Material UI

- Ant Design
- VueJS
- ReactJS
- Proficiency with Microsoft Office
- ATS Software

Certifications and Licenses

Tech Recruitment Certified Professional - DevSkiller

March 2022 to Present

ReactJS for Beginners - Simplilearn

January 2022 to Present

JavaScript for Beginners - Simplilearn

January 2022 to Present

Getting Started with ReactJS Components - Simplilearn

December 2021 to Present

Soft Skills Course - Jobberman Nigeria

April 2021 to Present

Certificate of Language Ability - Emmersion

March 2021 to Present

HTML/CSS and JavaScript - TestDome

March 2021 to Present